Beltain Jordaan

Greater London, UK BeltainJordaan@gmail.com

Personal Profile

Gameplay programmer specialising in C# and Unity game creation with over 4 and a half years of professional experience working at small to medium sized indie studios within London (with an additional 4 years working on solo/group projects and prototypes before that).

My Portfolio: <u>www.beltainjordaan.com</u>
Professional Work Experience

Gameplay Programmer – Payload Studios, *November 2021 – Present*

- Pitched and developed significant milestone features to be introduced in the game, creating example 3d models in addition to prototyping and presenting to the firm.
- Actively worked together with designers and artists to efficiently and clearly progress with development of new features.
- Developed and networked several gameplay features for PC, XBOX, Playstation, and Nintendo Switch systems.
- Worked extensively on the build pipeline including Python, Shell and Batch scripting work done on our Jenkins build server.
- Played a crucial role in the integration of our product with the Epic Games Store and implemented support for Epic Online Services and Crossplay.
- Proactively escalated and addressed bugs raised in public forums and collaborated closely with QA to swiftly resolve issues.
- Programmed specialised editor tools in Unity to improve efficiency and streamline design implementation pipelines.

Games Developer - Playtra Games, January 2020 - November 2021

- Adapted quickly to the internal practices of Playtra and exceeded personally set goals around learning the intricacies of the Unity Engine and C#.
- Coordinated with the team to develop bespoke systems to streamline workflow pipelines for level designers and artists.
- Worked together with the lead designer to suggest and implement proposed UI and UX systems and changes based on user feedback.
- Refactored scripts and large existing systems to accommodate future development, and was integral to brainstorming and prototyping new and innovative gameplay mechanics.
- Developed key combat mechanics, comprehensive save data and input management systems.
- Designed and created powerful procedural systems with clear user interfaces, as well as developed an extensive checkpoint management system.
- Optimised and configured the project to work across various consoles including the Nintendo Switch, XBOX One and platforms such as Steam.

Mobile Support Technician - Fidelity Group, September 2018 - December 2019

- Frequently assisted clients with high urgency technical issues, providing support in high pressure environments. I had excellent feedback from my clients and my team members for the support provided.
- Worked with a sizable team handling day-to-day operations for a large telecommunications group.

Supervisor - Starbucks, November 2017 - September 2018

- Managed the operations of the store for long shifts whilst simultaneously providing training and support to junior employees who had just joined the team.
- Frequently resolved conflict between team members and more excitable customers, though challenging, I was able to keep the team calm in more stressful situations and able to come to a conclusion which left the customer content and happy with our service.

Project Lead - Self Published AppStore Game, November 2017 - June 2018

- Directed the development and release of a 3D mobile endless runner in a team of three.
- Motivated and inspired the team to take a previously abandoned concept and transform it into a much larger project that was built to completion, whilst keeping the scope challenging, but also manageable and feasible.
- Developed a significant proportion of the final game mechanics, and created a large variety of the game's 3D assets.
- Undertook market research and subsequently created multiple types of promotional materials for the game's store page and a successful advertising campaign.

Key Skills and Competencies

- Clear and extensive knowledge with C# and Unity, with an understanding of Java, Python, C++, JavaScript and some other minor languages and platforms as well.
- 3D Modelling Experienced in creating biology and structural models using Blender3D, including armature rigging, animation, texturing and sculpting.
- Excellent communication and interpersonal skills. Able to handle delicate situations and convey complex ideas.
- For several years, I have coached and mentored team members and programmers of both junior and senior levels, assisting in the introduction of new concepts, tools, and methodologies to keep our knowledge and experience current and relevant.
- I possess a comprehensive understanding of all fields of the technical pipeline, spanning from 3D modelling, texturing, and animation to rigging, game design, and video editing.

Education

2015 - 2017 The Piggott School - Wargrave Maths Statistics, Computing and Biology A levels

2009-2015 Glenwood House Private School - George, Western Cape Maths, English, Afrikaans, Biology, Physics, Computing International Baccalaureates

Extra Achievements and Interests

- I enjoy prototyping and experimenting with new technical ideas and mechanics in the Unity engine and constantly challenge myself to improve my knowledge of it.
- Native speaker in English and a degree of Afrikaans, and also learning Japanese.
- Learned how to work with Arduinos and breadboard electronics to build basic circuits.
- Dungeon Master for a DnD group of five players where I create the story, balance encounters, create maps, homebrew monsters, dictate the pacing and keep each party member engaged for 5+ hour sessions on a near weekly basis.
- Co-creator of a popular steam workshop character mod for "Don't Starve Together" with over 43k unique subscribers.
- Created a competition winning modded map in Minecraft that was used on one of the largest minigame servers.